Relative pronouns are THAT, WHICH, WHO, WHOM
& WHOSE.
They are used to introduce more information
in a relative clause.
Relative clauses tell us more about people
and things.
Here is an example.
- The penetration test which we ran two weeks
ago has produced interesting results.
This sentence includes the relative pronoun
which.
It provides more information about the penetration
test.
This is what we call a relative clause.
Let’s change the sentence a little.
- The penetration test has produced interesting
results.
This sentence, in its basic form, does not
include the additional information and does
not have a relative pronoun.
Now, here’s something called a nominal relative
clause.
- That’s what I was talking about.
Here we are using the pronoun what to mean
the thing which or that I was talking about.
The thing and that have combined to form the
nominal relative pronoun what.
For nominal relative clauses, we can use WHAT,
WHEN, WHERE, HOW, WHO & WHY.
Here are some more examples.
- That’s not how I heard it.
Here somebody said something, and the way
you understand what they said is not the way
that I understand it.
- Building awareness in their employees is
what they should be doing.
The thing which they should be doing is building
awareness in their employees..
Or They should be building awareness in their
employees.
- It was when they connected the insecure
devices.
That’s how it happened.
Connecting the insecure devices created problems.
This is when the problems happened.
It’s also how the problems happened.
- Regular security awareness training is what
we need.
The thing that we need is regular security
awareness.
- That’s why I’m asking you.
Whatever sentence I said before this one is
the reason why I am asking you.
- That’s who I’m talking about.
That is the person I am talking about.
The most common nominal relative pronoun is
what.
It’s what you will hear the most.